

CONTACT

- RAIPUR, India 492099
- (091) 808-5966697
- ✓ Vikasranjankumar3291@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Relationship building
- Business development and planning
- · Coaching and mentoring
- Trained in consumer marketing
- Sales presentations
- Strategic planning

LANGUAGES

lindi[.]

Advanced (C1)

English:

Advanced (C1)

Vikas Ranjan Kumar

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Competent and Seasoned Banking professional with 17+ years of extencive experience in different geogaraphies, exposer and expertise in various parameter of Branch operation, Retail banking, Sales and Marketing, Business development, Customer Relationship, Copmplaint mangement, increasing Market Share outperform competition and achieving profitability.

WORK HISTORY

Area Sales Manager

06/2020 - Current

Axis Bank - Raipur, India

- Established strong relationships with channeles and key decision-makers to increase sales of unsecured loans in designated territory.
- Hired, trained and managed sales staff and administered and implemented compensation plan to support area sales goals.
- Analyzed sales data and kept up to date with market trends.
- Handelling a large team of 12SMs and 65Ros Helped team stay productive and focused on higher-value tasks to improve sales efficiency.

Regional head Sales

06/2012 - 06/2020

ICICI BANK - Raipur, India

- Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.
- served Icici bank for more than 8years, worked in diffrent -2 geographies and diffrent -2 profile, starting from Branch Operation Manaer, Branch Manager and Regional Head Sales.

Sr Relarionship Manager

01/2009 - 06/2012

IDBI Federal Life Insurance Co - Raipur, India

- Sucessfully handelled the Bancassurance channel for to increase the
 business.
- product presentation, Bank staff training, customer hendelling, Complain resolution, Conducted events and activities for product promotion and lead generation, from Sourcing to after sales services.

Sales Manager

09/2007 - 01/2009

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance Co - Raipur, India

- Conducted team meetings to reinforce goals and objectives and set clear expectations about policies and procedures.
- Targeted and prospected for new business through Branch channel ,telemarketing, individual creativity and innovation.

Insurance Associate

HDFC Life Insurance Company - Raipur, India

11/2006 - 09/2007

- Completed sales documentation and collected signatures to finalize purchases.
- Researched and resolved areas of concern for potential and existing clients.
- Participated and developed relationships with potential clients and channels to increase sales.
- Met sales targets month on month.
- Prepared insurance claim forms or related documents and reviewed for completeness.
- Earned higest incentives in pan india in fy 2006-07.

Sales officer

07/2006 - 11/2006

Bharti Airtel Ltd. - Raipur, India

- Enhanced sales operations through development of new sales strategies, cold calling techniques and customer follow-up
- Prepared sales reports with informative graphs and charts to outline key data.
- · Become Best sales officer of Circle.

EDUCATION

MBA: Marketing And Finance, 03/2005 Pt Ravi shankar shukla university – Raipur

Bcom: Commerce and Tax, 03/2003

Guru ghasidas University – DP VIPRA Bilaspur

12th: PCM, 03/2019

MP board bhopal - Kotma

10th, 03/1997

Mp board bhopal - SVMK kotma

CERTIFICATIONS

- IRDA
- AMFI

EXTRA CURRICULUM ACTIVITIES

· Participated and won prize in debate in several times.

PROJECT UNDERTAKEN

- Sucess of Govt policy to inroduce the Kisan credit card in chhattisgarh. (Under the Instuitional financial director ,CG Govt.)
- · Investor Attitude towards mutulfund.
- · Work culture in BSP Bhilai.

REFERENCE

· References available upon request